mycricket.com 2017-05-02

# Privacy Policy | Cricket

#### Effective June 16, 2016, Cricket Wireless Privacy Policy was updated. View the previous version >

* * *

#### Application of Policy

The following Privacy Policy applies to customers of Cricket Wireless, including customers who previously purchased service from Aio, Cricket Communications, Inc., or Leap Wireless International, Inc.

#### About Our Privacy Policy

Whenever you do something like buy one of Cricket Wireless ("Cricket") products or download an app, information is created. Because we know your privacy is important, we have a Privacy Policy to explain how we collect, use and protect that information. There is a quick summary below, and the entire policy is written in an FAQ format. We want to simplify this, so that you can make informed choices about your privacy, and then spend the rest of your time enjoying our products and service.

* * *

Effective June 16, 2016

Last Updated: May 9, 2016

* * *

#### Our privacy commitments

Our privacy commitments are fundamental to the way we do business every day. These apply to everyone who has a relationship with us - including customers and web site visitors.

  * We will protect your privacy and keep your personal information safe. We use encryption and other security safeguards to protect customer data.
  * We will not sell your personal information to anyone, for any purpose. Period.
  * We will fully disclose our privacy policy in plain language, and make our policy easily accessible to you. 
  * We will notify you of revisions to our privacy policy, in advance. No surprises. 
  * You have choices about how we use your information for marketing purposes. Customers are in control. 
  * We want to hear from you. You can send us questions or feedback on our privacy policy.  

#### A Quick Summary of Our Privacy Policy

Our privacy policy applies to your use of our products and services including www.cricketwireless.com. We will always provide you with prior notice of material changes to this Policy via a prominent notice on our site and/or a direct electronic mail or text communication. In order to do things like constantly improve our services, products and relationship with you, we may collect different types of information that help us learn more about how you use our offerings.

Here's some of the information we collect:

  * **Account Information** includes your name, address, telephone number, email address, service related details such as payment data, security codes, service history, and other information like that;
  * **Network Performance & Usage Information** tells us how you use our network, our products, and our services, and how well our equipment and network is performing;
  * **Web Browsing & Wireless Application Information** tells us about the websites you visit and the mobile applications you use on our network;
  * **Location Information** tells us where your wireless device is located.

Here are the three basic ways we collect it:

  * We get information from you when you do things like make a purchase from us;
  * We collect it from how you use our products and services;
  * Other sources, like credit agencies, marketing companies, and other service providers provide it to us.

Here are just some of the ways we use it. To:

  * Provide services and improve your customer experience;
  * Bill you for your services;
  * Respond to your questions;
  * Address network integrity and security issues;
  * Do research and analysis to maintain, protect, develop and improve our network;
  * Let you know about service updates, offers, and promotions;
  * Improve entertainment options;
  * Deliver Relevant Advertising;
  * Create External Marketing & Analytics Reports
  * Assist in the prevention and investigation of illegal activities and violations of our Terms of Service or Acceptable Use Policies.

Some examples of who we share your Personal Information with:

  * **Affiliated companies.** Cricket is an AT&T company and we share your Personal Information with AT&T and other companies in the AT&T family, commonly referred to as affiliates, for a variety of purposes, including the marketing of products and services to you. 
    * Cricket already offers you certain choices and controls about marketing and advertising here. If you opt-out through these options, AT&T and its affiliates will also honor that opt-out with respect to personal information they may receive from Cricket for advertising or marketing purposes. If you are also an AT&T customer, making a choice here will not change any existing choices you may have made separately with AT&T.
  * **Other companies** that perform services on our behalf only as needed for them to perform those services. We require them to protect your information consistent with our Policy.
  * **Other companies and entities, to** :
    * Respond to 911 requests and other emergencies or exigencies;
    * Comply with court orders and other legal process;
    * Assist with identity verification, and preventing fraud and identity theft;
    * Enforce our agreements and property rights; and
    * Obtain payment for products and services.

Details on Personal and Anonymous & Aggregate Information

  * What is Personal Information? Information that identifies or reasonably can be used to identify you.
  * What is Anonymous? This is information that doesn't identify you and can't reasonably be used to identify you specifically.
  * What is Aggregate? We take a whole bunch of people's data and combine it into anonymous groups or categories.
  * How we use this information? We use and share this information in many ways including research, media analysis and retail marketing and Relevant Advertising. This data is also included in External Marketing & Analytics Reports
  * Want to learn more? Go here.

Our commitment to protecting your data

  * We don't sell your Personal Information to anyone for any purpose. Period.
  * We keep your Personal Information in our business records while you are a customer, or until it is no longer needed for business, tax, or legal purposes.
  * We will keep your information safe using encryption or other appropriate security controls.

Our Online Privacy Policy for Children

  * We want you to know that we don't knowingly collect personally identifying information from anyone under the age of 13 unless we first obtain permission from the child's parent or legal guardian.

Your Choices & Controls

  * You have choices about which types of advertising you get from us;
  * You can control whether your anonymous information is used in our External Marketing & Analytics Reports;
  * You can choose whether to receive marketing calls, emails or text messages from us;
  * You have a choice about how we use your Customer Proprietary Network Information

More information about our use of CPNI and your choices about that use is available here:

  * Definitions
  * Scope of this Policy
  * The Information We Collect, How We Collect It, And How We Use It
  * Information Sharing
  * Location Information
  * Aggregate & Anonymous Information
  * Customer Controls & Choices
  * Online Privacy Policy for Children
  * Data Protection & Security
  * Changes

#### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 entitles California customers to request information concerning whether a business has disclosed Personal Information to any third parties for their' direct marketing purposes. As stated in this Privacy Policy, we will not sell your Personal Information to other companies and we will not share it with unaffiliated AT&T companies for their direct marketing purposes without your consent.

#### California Web Site Data Collection & "Do Not Track" Notices

Web Site Data Collection: We do not knowingly allow other parties to collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites when you use our websites and services. Cricket provides information about the opt-out choices it makes available [here](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/7723 "opt-out choices").  

"Do Not Track" Notice: Because the providers of "do not track" and similar signals do not yet operate according to common, industry-accepted standards, Cricket currently does not respond to those signals. For more information on Do Not Track, please visit [www.allaboutdnt.com](http://www.allaboutdnt.com/ "All about Do Not Track").

California customers who wish to request further information about our compliance with these requirements or have questions or concerns about our privacy practices and policies may contact us at [privacypolicy@cricketwireless.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cricketwireless.com "privacy policy email address"), or write to us at Cricket Privacy Policy, 1120 20th Street, N.W., 10th Floor, Washington, DC 20036

* * *

## Our Cricket Privacy Policy in easy, FAQ format.

We understand that everyone thinks that privacy policies are long, complicated and difficult to understand. So we're going to try to make this as simple as possible. ****

#### **DEFINITIONS**

Let's start with what we mean when we say:

Aggregate Information: Information that we combine into anonymous groups of customers or users. One way to think of it is in terms of a survey or opinion poll. Aggregate information would tell you that 80 percent of the people voted for a candidate, but not who actually voted. These groups are large enough to reasonably prevent individuals from being identified.

Anonymous Information: Information that doesn't directly identify and can't reasonably be used to identify an individual customer or user.

Customer: Anyone who purchases or uses our products or services. When a customer purchases retail products or services for use by others, those individuals also are customers.

Mobile Application: A software application that runs on smartphones, tablet computers or other mobile devices and that allows users to access a variety of services and information.

Personal Information: Information that directly identifies or reasonably can be used to figure out the identity of a customer or user, such as your name, address, phone number and email address.

Relevant Advertising: Uses aggregate information about groups of people (like age, ethnicity, income range, where those groups live and work, and their interests) to develop advertising that is more likely to be useful to that group. It does not use individual data about what a specific person might like. "Online behavioral advertising" is one type of relevant advertising. It uses interest categories based on the websites visited by groups of people to deliver advertising online.

User: Anyone who visits our websites or uses our mobile applications.

Website: And other terms like "Internet site," "site" and "web page" all mean the same thing, namely any page or location on the Internet, no matter what device (cell phone, tablet, laptop, PC, etc.) or protocol (http, WAP, ftp or other) is used to access the page or location.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT THE SCOPE OF THIS POLICY

##### 1\. What does this Policy cover?

This Privacy Policy covers our practices regarding the information we collect about our customers and users (how we collect it and how we use it). Use of our products and services, as well as visits to our websites, are subject to this Privacy Policy.

##### 2\. What about my family members and other users of my Cricket account? Does this Policy apply to them?

Yes. You're responsible for making sure all family members or other users under your account understand and agree to this Policy. Get everyone together and talk about it. Or, send it by email to make sure they're on board. Hang it on the fridge. Up to you, just share it!

##### 3\. When is your information not covered by this Policy?

Any time you give information to companies other than Cricket. Some examples are:

  * When you download applications or make purchases from other companies while using our wireless services;
  * When you go to a non-Cricket website from one of our websites or applications (by clicking on a link or an advertisement, for example);
  * If you use public forums such as social networking services, Internet bulletin boards, chat rooms, or blogs, the information is publicly available, and we cannot prevent distribution and use of that information by other parties;
  * Information about your location, usage and the numbers you dial when you're out and about and roaming on the network of another company;
  * When you purchase or use non-Cricket products (such as wireless devices, internet browsers and mobile applications) in combination with Cricket services;
  * When we license our brand to other companies for their use in marketing and selling certain non-Cricket products and services, information you give those companies is not covered by this Policy.

##### 4\. Can my information be covered by this policy and other privacy policies at the same time?

Yes, that can happen. For example:

  * Sometimes we will provide a service with other companies. In that case your information may be subject to this Policy and that of the other companies.
  * If you purchase one of our products or services from a retail store, any information you provide to them may be subject to both their policy and ours.
  * We think it's a great idea to take a look at the privacy policies of any companies you do business with to learn how they use your information.

##### 5\. What about business customers?

We may have written product or service agreements with business customers that contain specific provisions about confidentiality, security or handling of information. When one of these agreements differs from or conflicts with this Policy, the terms of those agreements will apply. In all other instances, the terms of this Policy apply.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT, HOW WE COLLECT IT AND HOW WE USE IT

##### 1\. What information do we collect?  

We may collect different types of information based on your use of our products and services and on our business relationship with you.

Account Information:

  * Contact Information that allows us to communicate with you. We get this information when you order or register for our services. This would include information like your name, address, telephone number, and email address.
  * Billing Information related to your financial relationship with us, such as the services we provide to you, the telephone numbers you call and text, your payment history, your credit history, your credit card numbers, Social Security number, security codes, and your service history.

Technical & Usage Information related to the services we provide to you, including information about how you use our network, services, products or websites. Some examples include:

  * **Equipment Information** that identifies your equipment on our network, such as equipment type, device IDs, device status, serial numbers, settings, configuration, and software.
  * **Network Performance & Usage Information** about the operation of the equipment, services and applications you use on our network.  Examples of this might include wireless device location, the number of text messages sent and received, voice minutes used, bandwidth used, and resources you use when uploading, downloading or streaming data to and from the Internet.  
  * Some Network Performance & Usage Information and some Billing Information is  **Customer Proprietary Network Information or "CPNI."**  CPNI  is information that relates to the quantity, configuration, type, destination, location and amount of use of the telecommunications services you purchase from us, as well as the information contained in your bills for those services. We collect CPNI in the normal course of providing you with telecommunications services. Your telephone number, name and address are not CPNI.
  * **Web Browsing & Mobile Application Information **such as IP addresses, URLs, data transmission rates and delays.  We also learn about the pages you visit, the links or advertisements you see and follow, the search terms you enter, how often you open an application, how long you spend using the app, and other similar information.
    * **Social Media Widgets** such as the Facebook button or widget such as the Share this button or other interactive mini-programs that run on our Web site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
    * If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address.  We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site.  Cricket stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email, and tracking the success of our referral program.
  * **Location Information** includes the whereabouts of your wireless device as well your ZIP-code and street address. Location information is generated when your device communicates with cell towers, Wi-Fi routers or access points and/or with other technologies, including the satellites that comprise the Global Positioning System.  

##### 2\. How Do You Collect Information?

In three basic ways:

  * **You Give It To Us  **when you make a purchase or set up an account with us.
  * **We Automatically Collect Information  **when you use our network, products and services.  For example, we use network tools to collect your call records, as well as other types of Technical & Usage information. We also use cookies, web server logs and other technologies.
  * **We Obtain Information from Outside Sources**  like credit reports, marketing mailing lists, and commercially available geographic and demographic information.

##### 3\. How Do You Use My Information?

We use your information to improve your experience and to make our business stronger.  Some examples include:

Providing and managing your services, responding to your questions, and addressing problems;

Delivering customized content, Relevant Advertising and personalized offers for products and services that may be of interest to you;

  * Communicating service updates, offers and promotions;
  * Protecting network integrity and security, ensuring quality control, optimizing capacity, and preventing misuse;
  * Network enhancement planning, engineering and technical support;
  * Conducting research and analysis for maintaining, protecting and developing our network and our services;
  * Preventing illegal activities, suspected fraud, and potential threats to our network and our customers' networks;
  * Investigating violations of our Terms of Service, Acceptable Use Policies, or other service conditions or restrictions; and
  * Protecting the safety of any person.

##### 4\. Do you use the information I store using your cloud services?

If we provide cloud services, we will only use the information you store to provide you with that service, unless we first get your permission to use it for something different. ****

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT INFORMATION SHARING

##### 1\. Do you share my Personal Information with other companies for them to market to me?

We may share your Personal Information with AT&T and other AT&T affiliates for a variety of purpose, including so that they can market products and services to you. Except for AT&T and other AT&T affiliates, we will not share your Personal Information with other companies for them to use for the marketing of their own products and services without your consent.

##### 2\. Are there any other times when you might provide my Personal Information to other companies or entities?

Yes. We share your Personal Information with companies that perform services for us, like processing your bill.  Because we take our responsibility to safeguard your Personal Information seriously, we do not allow those companies to use it for any purpose other than to perform those services, and we require them to protect it in a way consistent with this Policy.

Companies that perform these services may be located outside the United States, or the jurisdiction where you reside. If your Personal Information is shared with these companies, it could be accessible to government authorities according to the laws that govern those jurisdictions.

There are also occasions when we provide Personal Information to other companies or other entities, such as government agencies, credit bureaus and collection agencies, without your consent. Some examples include sharing to:

  * Comply with court orders, subpoenas, lawful discovery requests and other legal or regulatory requirements, and to enforce our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  * Obtain payment or make refunds for products and services that appear on your Cricket billing statements;
  * Enforce our agreements and protect our rights or property;
  * Assist with identity verification and email address validation;
  * Notify, respond or provide information (including location information) to a responsible governmental entity in emergency or exigent circumstances or in situations involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury; and
  * Notify the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children of information concerning child pornography of which we become aware through the provision of our services.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT MY INFORMATION & ADVERTISING

##### 1\. Do you use my information to send me advertising?

Yes. We may use information like the preferences you have expressed and interests you have demonstrated on our websites, in our stores, and through use of our products and services, to provide you with marketing information and advertisements for Cricket products and services. Those ads may be delivered on our websites and mobile applications. This is called "first party" advertising. It is part of our service relationship and you are not able to opt-out from this type of advertising.

Our advertising partners may also use anonymous information gathered through cookies and similar technologies, as well as other anonymous and aggregate information that either of us may have to help us tailor the ads you see on non-Cricket sites. For example, if you see an ad from us on a non-Cricket sports-related website, you may later receive an ad for sporting equipment delivered by us on a different website. This is called "online behavioral advertising", which is a type of Relevant Advertising.

##### 2\. What are cookies, Flash cookies, Web beacons, widgets, and server log files, how do you use them, and can I limit the collection of data from my computer on web sites that use that information for advertising?

Let's start with what we mean when we use the word "cookie" and other related terms:

  * Cookies are small data files. Websites place them in your browser to recognize your computer or mobile device when you return to that site. Cookies are created to keep track of your movements within the site, help you resume where you left off, remember your registered username, preferences and other customizations.
  * There are a couple of important things to remember about cookies:
    * Disabling cookies may prevent you from using specific features on some websites. You'll need to perform the opt out procedure if you opt out of a program or service and then change computers or Web browsers, or clear or erase the digital "cookie" that lets us know you opted out.
    * Local Storage Cookies. Local Storage is a convenient, flexible, secure and faster way to store HTTP state data. It is a method by which our web pages locally store named key/value pairs in a user's web browser. Local storage on ATT.com is mainly used to store and retrieve data in HTML pages from our domains. Local storage data is session-based and will not persist once the session is over and the browser is closed.
  * Flash Cookies (also called Local Shared Objects or "LSOs") are data files similar to cookies, except that they can store more complex data. They are used to remember your settings, preferences and usage, and other similar services. Flash cookies allow functionality and availability of certain services. If disabled, these services may not function correctly. While browser cookies may be removed or blocked via web browser settings, flash cookies operate differently. Please note that setting the Flash Player to restrict or limit acceptance of Flash LSOs may reduce or impede the functionality of some Flash applications. To learn more about how to manage flash cookies, you can visit the Adobe website and make changes at Global Storage Settings Panel.
  * Web beacons are small graphic images on a Web page or in an email. They can be used for things like recording the pages and advertisements that users click on, or tracking how well an e-mail marketing campaign performs.
  * A widget is a small program or application that can be embedded in a web page. It can provide real-time information, such as stock quotes or weather reports. Widgets are often provided by a third party and allow them to collect data about users viewing that page.
  * A server log records your web activity by your computer or mobile device and plays a key role in improving web page performance and introducing new features. For example, it may record which search terms you've entered, or the links you've clicked on. It may also record your browser information, such as your IP address, device type, how long you spend on a Web page, and your browser's cookies.
  * Some websites have "social network or other third-party plug-ins." These plug-ins may provide information back to those sites, even if you don't click on or interact with the plug-in. It may also apply even if you don't have an account with them. Social networks or third parties may use an identifier when transmitting from your browser. This might include information about your browser type, operating system, device type, IP address and the URL of the web page where the plug-in appears. If you use social networking tools or sites, we recommend you take a moment to familiarize yourself with their privacy policies.

**Managing Cookies**

Most browsers will allow you to delete, disable and choose what cookies can be placed on your computer. If you want more information about controlling cookies, visit [http://www.AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "information about cookies").

To learn how to manage cookies for:

  * Individual Browsers 
  * Flash Player
    * <http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security/>

##### 3\. Do you use my information for other types of Relevant Advertising?

Yes. Cricket also uses information we get through your use of our products and services, from our advertising partners, and information like your age and gender to deliver Relevant Advertising that is not online behavioral advertising. We combine your anonymous information with that of other users into aggregate "audience segments". These segments are based on particular interests and/or factual characteristics that everyone in that audience segment is likely to share. We might use that information to send you advertisements that are relevant to those interests or characteristics.

We are careful to create Relevant Advertising with aggregate audience segments that are large enough that you can't be identified individually.

##### 4\. Do you use the location of my device for advertising purposes?

Yes. Cricket uses information about the locations you visit in order to create combined wireless location interest characteristics that can be used to provide Relevant Advertising to you and others like you.

Location characteristics are types of locations like "movie theaters". People who live in or are associated with a particular geographic area (a city, ZIP-code or ZIP+ 4 code, for example) might appear to have a high interest in movies, thanks to collective information that shows wireless devices from that area are often located in the vicinity of movie theaters. We might create a "movies characteristic", and deliver movie ads to the people who live in or are associated with that area.  

We may associate your wireless device with a particular geographic area, such as a city, ZIP-code, or ZIP + 4 code, based on your billing address or the cell towers you connect with most frequently. Cricket does not keep a record of the places you have visited.

In addition to other privacy protections, the process we use to create our audience segment includes a requirement that the ZIP + 4 or other geographic area to which a wireless location is assigned must contain a minimum of 25 households.  ZIP + 4 codes with less than 25 households are combined with other ZIP + 4 codes to satisfy this requirement.

##### 5\. What's in it for me?

Just like the name says, you get advertising that's more relevant to your interests. For example, if a particular audience segment, like adults between the ages of 21 and 25 with a certain income range, has demonstrated a greater interest in movies than other segments, we might send them a movie ad for a movie geared toward young adults. This is just one way we deliver content that's more relevant.  

##### 6\. Do I ever have a chance to tell you what I'm personally interested in?

When we add new offers that use your Personal Information to customize and deliver individually tailored advertising and promotions to you, we'll let you know, so you can decide if you'd like to participate.  For example, in the future we may offer you a service that allows you to sign up to receive text-message offers from business that are near your current location and match up to interests you select. Or we could offer you free or discounted services in exchange for the use of your Personal Information for advertising and other similar purposes. We promise, before we use any of your Personal Information (including information we gather as an Internet service provider) for such purposes, we will always give you the opportunity to make an informed choice about whether to participate

##### 7\. What information do you provide to advertisers?

Cricket may provide reports to advertisers and other business customers about the success of its advertising campaigns. Those reports contain aggregate information about the number of times a particular ad was viewed, when it was viewed, whether it was viewed on a mobile device or a computer, demographics associated with the viewing audience and other similar information. Your anonymous information will not be included in aggregate reports about the success of Relevant Advertising campaigns if you have opted-out of Relevant Advertising delivered by Cricket or its advertising partners.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT LOCATION INFORMATION

##### 1\. What is location information?

Exactly what it sounds like! It includes your ZIP-code and street address, as well as the whereabouts of your wireless device.

##### 2\. How is it used?

We use it in all kinds of ways, here are some examples:    

  * **We Provide Wireless Voice and Data Services:** We monitor, collect and use wireless location information, together with other information we get from our network and your wireless device, to maintain and improve our network. We also might use location information with your consent to provide you with a customized experience. For example, if we provide 411 Directory Assistance and you dial the telephone number for a particular business; we might use your wireless location information to return the number of the business location closest to you.
  * **Location Based Services (LBS):** Your device can be used to access a ton of services based on location. We offer these services via applications that have been pre-loaded or downloaded by you on your device. LBS also may be provided via text message or other functionality.  We'll give you prior notice and ask for your consent when your location is used or shared. The form of consent may vary, but will be appropriate for the type of Cricket LBS you use.  
  *  We use it for  **Advertising**.

##### 3\. How accurate is wireless location information?

It depends on the technology we're using. For example, we can locate your device based on the cell tower that's serving you. The range could be up to 1,000 meters in any direction from the tower in urban areas, and up to 10,000 meters in rural areas.  Wi-Fi networks provide more accurate location information, associating you with the place where the network is located like a coffee shop or to an area within or around that place.

Some services require more precise information.  So for those we develop a more precise estimate of location by associating the serving cell tower ID with other information, like the latitude and longitude of the tower, radio frequency parameters, GPS information and timing differences in radio signals. Depending on a variety of factors, those methods may estimate the location of your device to within 30 to 1000 meters.

##### 4\. Are you the only ones who can locate my wireless device?  

Other companies may also be able to locate your device.  For example, your handset manufacturer and your operating system provider may be able to locate your device.  If you download mobile applications, those apps may be able to obtain your location directly from your handset or the operating system. Mobile applications that give you access to your employer's network, may also give your employer the ability to locate your device.  

We urge you to review Policies of all providers.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT AGGREGATE AND ANONYMOUS INFORMATION

##### 1\. Where do you get anonymous information?

Sometimes we'll collect information about how you use our products using cookies and other similar technologies. This information doesn't include your Personal Information and is considered anonymous.

When we collect information that identifies you personally, we may anonymize it for certain purposes.  We remove data fields (such as name, address and telephone number) that can reasonably be used to identify you. We also use a variety of statistical techniques and operational controls to anonymize data.  Anonymizing information is one of the tools we use to protect your privacy.

##### 2\. Tell me more about aggregate information.

Aggregate information is a form of anonymous information.  We combine data that meet certain criteria into anonymous groups. For example, we might want to compare how customers in Beverly Hills, CA (or any city, county or ZIP-code) use their cell phones to how customers in Boulder, CO use their cell phones.  In order to do that, we would combine customer data in each of the geographies into anonymous groups and look at all that aggregate data to understand how the two groups are different or similar.

##### 3\. Do you share anonymous or aggregate information?

Yes, we may share this information with other companies and entities for specific uses, which may include:

  * Universities, laboratories, think tanks and other entities that conduct networking, social, behavioral, environmental and other types of scientific research, for the purpose of creating fundamental new knowledge;
  * Municipalities, government or other entities that may use this data for purposes such as municipal and transportation planning, and emergency and disaster response coordination.

We share this information in external reports like our External Marketing and Analytics Reports and Metric Reports.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT EXTERNAL MARKETING AND ANALYTICS REPORTS

##### 1\. Tell me more about the External Marketing & Analytics Program.

  * We use aggregate information to create External Marketing & Analytics Reports that we may sell to other companies for their own marketing, advertising or other similar uses.    
  * These reports may be a combination of information from wireless and Wi-Fi locations, website browsing and mobile application usage and other information we have about you and other customers. You have a choice about whether your anonymous information is included in these reports.

Some examples of External Marketing & Analytics Reports include:

  * Reports for retail businesses that show the number of wireless devices in or near their store locations by time of day and day of the week, together with demographic characteristics of the users (such as age and gender) in those groups; and 
  * Reports for device manufacturers that combine information such as device type, make and model with demographic and regional location information to reflect the popularity of particular device types with various customer segments.

##### 2\. Do you provide companies with individual anonymous data as part of your External Marketing & Analytics Program?

Yes. When we provide individual anonymous information to businesses, we require that they only use it to provide aggregate reports, and for no other purpose. We also require businesses to agree they will not attempt to identify any person using this information, and that they will handle it in a secure manner, consistent with this Policy.

##### 3\. Do you use my anonymous information in other types of external reports?

We may use your anonymous information to provide Metrics Reports to our service suppliers. For example, we may license entertainment content, like music programming, from content providers. Our agreements with those providers may require us to provide them with Metrics Reports containing measurements and other statistics about the number of customers who used particular content at a particular time and other similar information. These reports are considered part of the underlying service and we do not sell them to other customers or suppliers.

#### OUR ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY FOR CHILDREN

##### 1\. Do you collect information about my children's use?

We do not knowingly collect personally identifying information from anyone under the age of 13 unless we first obtain permission from the child's parent or legal guardian.

##### 2\. What happens when my child is using an account not registered to them?

Internet and wireless devices and services purchased for family use may be used by children without our knowledge. When that happens, information collected appears to us to be associated with the adult customer who subscribes to our services, and will be treated as the adult's information under this Policy.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT DATA PROTECTION AND SECURITY

##### 1\. Do we sell your Personal Information?

We don't sell your Personal Information to anyone, for any purpose. Period.

##### 2\. How long do we keep your Personal Information?

We keep your Personal Information as long as we need for business, tax, or legal purposes. After that, we destroy it by making it unreadable or undecipherable

##### 3\. What safeguards does Cricket have in place?

  * We've worked hard to protect your information.  And we've established electronic and administrative safeguards designed to make the information we collect secure. Some examples of those safeguards include:
  * All of our employees are subject to the Code of Business Conduct (COBC) and certain state-mandated codes of conduct. Under the COBC, all employees must follow the laws, rules, regulations, court and/or administrative orders that apply to our business including, specifically, the legal requirements and company policies surrounding the privacy of communications and the security and privacy of your records. We take this seriously, and any of our employees who fail to meet the standards we've set in the COBC are subject to disciplinary action. That includes dismissal.
  * We've implemented technology and security features and strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of your Personal Information. Some examples are: 
  * Maintaining and protecting the security of computer storage and network equipment, and our security procedures require employee user names and passwords to access sensitive data; 
  * Applying encryption or other appropriate security controls to protect Personal Information when stored or transmitted by us; 
  * Limiting access to Personal Information to only those with jobs requiring such  access; and 
  * Requiring caller/online authentication before providing Account Information so that only you or someone who knows your Account Information will be able to access or change the information.
  * Although we strive to keep your Personal Information secure, no security measures are perfect, and we cannot guarantee that your Personal Information will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Policy (for example, as the result of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate the law or this Policy).

##### 4\. Will you notify me in case of a security breach?

Laws and regulations guide us in how to give you notification when certain types of sensitive information are involved in a security breach. We will provide you with notice in accordance with these laws and regulations.

##### 5\. Can I review, correct, update or remove my Personal Information and Deactivate my account?

Yes. We are happy to help you review, correct, update, or remove the information associated with your account and billing records as appropriate.  We may still retain your information in our files however, as required for various purposes including dispute resolution, enforcing user agreements and other business, technical or legal requirements. Please login to your Cricket account for assistance. If you need further assistance please contact us at [privacypolicy@cricketwireless.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cricketwireless.com). We will respond to all requests within 30 days.

##### 6\. Have your privacy practices been certified?

Yes, and we're very proud of it! TRUSTe has awarded Cricket Wireless the TRUSTe Privacy Seal. As an independent third party, TRUSTe's mission is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. Our TRUSTe Privacy Seal signifies that TRUSTe has reviewed our Privacy Policy and practices for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/ "TRUSTe's program requirements"). These include transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your Personal Information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through www.cricketwireless.com and does not cover our mobile applications.

#### QUESTIONS ABOUT FUTURE CHANGES

##### 1\. What happens if there is a change in corporate ownership?

Information about our customers and users, including Personal Information, may be shared and transferred as part of any merger, acquisition, sale of company assets, or transition of service to another provider. This also applies in the unlikely event of an insolvency, bankruptcy, or receivership in which customer and user records would be transferred to another entity as a result of such a proceeding.

##### 2\. Will I be notified if there are changes to this policy?

We may update this Privacy Policy as necessary to reflect changes we make and to satisfy legal requirements. We will post a prominent notice of the change on our websites. We will provide you with other appropriate notice of important changes at least 30 days before the effective date.

#### YOUR CHOICES & CONTROLS

##### 1\. You can choose not to receive some types of advertising online or on your wireless device.

  * Opt-out of all Relevant Advertising delivered on your mobile device here. You'll need to opt-out on **each** mobile device you want to exclude.
  * Opt-out of online behavioral advertising provided by Cricket and other advertisers by clicking the [Advertising Choices](https://info.evidon.com/pub_info/7723 "advertising choices") link at the bottom of our web pages.
  * Opt-out of online behavioral advertising from many other ad networks at the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) [site](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "network advertising initiative site").
  * When you see online ads for Cricket products and services that display this icon [](http://www.aboutads.info/ "about online ads"), click and you will get information on how to [opt-out](http://www.aboutads.info/ "opt out").

##### 2\. Do I have choices about receiving first party advertisements from Cricket?

Because first party advertising is part of the service you receive when you visit our websites and use our mobile applications, we don't offer an opt-out for first party advertising.

##### 3\. You can also choose not to receive other types of marketing from Cricket.

We realize that unwanted marketing contacts can be a hassle and we've worked hard to meet the expectations of customers and potential customers who have expressed a desire to limit certain types of solicitation communications from us.

**Email:** Every marketing email we send contains instructions and a link that will allow you to stop additional marketing emails for that product or service type.  You also can unsubscribe from Cricket marketing emails here.

**Text Messages and MMS:** Opt-out of Cricket marketing text message and MMS contacts by replying "stop" to any message. You can also opt-out here.

**Federal Do Not Call:** The FTC maintains a National Do Not Call Registry at [donotcall.gov](http://www.donotcall.gov/ "do not call federal government registry"), and your state may maintain its own Do Not Call Registry. Putting your number on these Registries also may limit our Cricket telemarketing calls to that number.

**Postal Mail:** To limit postal mail solicitations, you can opt out here. With this limitation you will continue to receive legal notices, product updates and other similar correspondence, and you may still receive some promotional mailings

All of our practices are designed to satisfy state and federal legal requirements limiting marketing contacts. Those laws and regulations, such as the requirements governing the state and federal "Do Not Call" lists, generally permit companies to contact their own current and, in some cases, former customers, even when those customers are listed on the federal and state "Do Not Call" lists.

##### 4\. Do I have choices about your use of my CPNI?

Yes. More information about our use of CPNI and your choices about that use is available here. Restricting our use of your CPNI will not eliminate all types of our marketing contacts.

##### 5\. Can I choose to exclude my anonymous information from your External Marketing & Analytics and other similar reports?

Yes. Click here to opt-out. This opt-out also applies to the sharing of your anonymous information with other companies for their use in creating marketing and analytics reports. Although this opt out does not apply to Metrics Reports, it will apply if we combine Metrics Report information with other customer information (like demographics) to create reports that we provide to our business customers or service suppliers.

#### HOW TO CONTACT US ABOUT THIS POLICY

  * We encourage you to contact us directly at either of these addresses below for any questions about this Privacy Policy.
  * Email us at [privacypolicy@cricketwireless.com](mailto:privacypolicy@cricketwireless.com "privacy policy email address")
  * Write to us at Cricket Privacy Policy, 1120 20th Street, N.W., 10th Floor, Washington, DC 20036.
  * For questions not related to privacy Contact our Customer Service team. You also can access your online account for additional service options.
  * If you do not receive acknowledgment of your privacy inquiry or your inquiry is not addressed to your satisfaction, you may contact TRUSTe through the [TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request "contact TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process"). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison to resolve your concerns.
  * You also have the option of filing a complaint with the FTC Bureau of Consumer Protection, using an [online form](https://www.ftccomplaintassistant.gov/ "FTC online form"), or by calling toll-free 877.FTC.HELP (877.328.4357; TTY: 866.653.4261). Other rights and remedies also may be available to you under federal or other applicable laws.
